Guide to the William F. Rothwell Jr. Papers, 1959-1985
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
William F. Rothwell Jr. Papers
1959-1985
Rothwell, William F., Jr., 1920-2001
0.5 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Librettos, letters of commendation, and programs from Rothwell's work with the Experimental Theatre of Vassar College
Biographical Note
William F. Rothwell Jr., born in Kansas City, Missouri on November 17, 1920, taught in the Vassar College Department of Drama from 1957 until his retirement in 1991. The son of William Francis Rothwell and Frances Eleanor Meade, he served in the U.S. Army from 1942-46 as a tech sergeant. A graduate of the University of Arizona, he earned his Ph.D. at the Yale University School of Drama in 1953. From 1954 until 1957, he was an instructor in drama at the University of California at Berkeley. Coming to Vassar as an Instructor, he became an Assistant Professor in 1959, Associate Professor in 1966, and Professor in 1977. In addition to teaching, he was chair of the drama department on a rotating basis, translated several operas from French and Italian into English for staging at Vassar, and directed many plays, operas and other musical productions. Beginning in 1968, Rothwell was the director of the Experimental Theater at Vassar. Locally, he served on the boards of the Hudson Valley Playwright Music Theater and the Dutchess County Landmarks Association. Rothwell died on May 25, 2001 in Poughkeepsie, NY.
Scope and Content Note
Librettos, letters of commendation,and programs from Rothwell's work with the Experimental Theatre of Vassar College
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Places:
Vassar College. Experimental Theatre
VCL Categories
Theater, Drama and Film; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Jessica Kemm, September 2009.
Acquisition Information
Gift from Edward Reilly via the Sarah Canino/Music Library, Vassar College, August 13, 2004.
Container List
- Letters of Commendation and Thanks, 1959-1985 (Folder 1.1)
- Programs, ca. 1960-1975 (Folder 1.2)
- Librettos- La Cantera (Angelina), n.d. (Folder 1.3)
- Librettos- The Impressarion from Smyrna, n.d. (Folder 1.4)
- Librettos- The Maid of the Mill, ca. 1966 (Folder 1.5)
- Librettos- The Maid of the Mill - Original Lyrics and Music (Folder 1.6)
- Librettos- The Passionate Pasha (Le Cadi dupé), n.d. (Folder 1.7)
- Librettos- Rosina, 1976 (Folder 1.8)
- Librettos- The Trimph of True Love (L'Ivrone Corrige), ca. 1970 (Folder 1.9)
- Librettos- L'Ivrone Corrige - Original Lyrics and Music (Folder 1.10)
- Photos of an unidentified production, n.d. (Folder 1.11)
- Miscellaneous, 1971, n.d. (Folder 1.12)